A remarkable true story of human space exploration
Searching for Skylab, America's Forgotten Triumph is a documentary,
history, family film directed by Dwight Steven-Boniecki.
The first American space station Skylab is found in
pieces scattered in Western Australia.
Putting these pieces back together and re-tracing the Skylab program back to its
very conception reveals the cornerstone of human space exploration.
Self - Skylab-2 Scientist Pilot (NASA Astronaut),
played by Joseph P. (Joe) Kerwin.
Self - Skylab-2 Pilot (NASA Astronaut), played by Paul J. Weitz.
Self - Skylab-3 Pilot (NASA Astronaut), played by Jack R. Lousma.
Self - Skylab-3 Scientist Pilot (NASA Astronaut), played by Owen Garriott.
Self - Skylab-4 Commander (NASA Astronaut), played by Gerald P. (Jerry) Carr.
Self - Skylab-4 Scientist Pilot (NASA Astronaut),
played by Edward George Gibson.
Searching for Skylab - America's Forgotten Triumph is a 2019
documentary about the 1970s American space station Skylab.
It was written by Carl Alessi and directed by Dwight
Steven-Boniecki and partly crowdfunded.
Searching for Skylab was created to bring attention to the important role
Skylab played in the development of human spaceflight programs.
Of Skylab, Steven-Boniecki said, "Hundreds of hours of video and audio recordings exist from it, yet it is unlikely that you've seen or heard much of it."
A preview of the first
working version of Searching for Skylab was screened at Spacefest, in Tucson, Arizona, July 5, 2018 to a crowd of space experts, astronauts and their families.
In November 2018, shortly before the film's completion, a sneak peek of the movie’s working
version was presented at the Science Late Show at the Kosmos Kino in Zürich.
The finished documentary was released February 8, 2019, the 45th
anniversary of the splashdown of the last Skylab crew.
The film explores themes of hero, nasa, space suit, space travel, space mission.